Maneesh Kumar Pandey

9899419572, 78392249 | maneeshbaba@gmail.com | C6-528, Arihant Anmol CHS, Kharwai Naka, Badlapur East, Badlapur Thane,India,421503

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Sr. Software Engineer (IT-Analyst) with 10+ years of experience and demonstrated history of working in Business Process Management, Release Management, Data analyst and production support. Responsible for planning, designing, scheduling, deploying, and controlling software releases. Ensures that release teams efficiently deliver the applications and upgrades required by the business while maintaining the integrity of the existing production environment.

EXPERIENCE

Release Manager, L&T Finance Services, May 2022-Current Mumbai

- Plan the release of project deliverables and release life cycle.
- Communicate the project-related tasks such as plans, timelines, requirements, etc. between different teams.
- Coordinate the release schedule and resources required depending upon the third-party applications, defect backlogs, planned releases, and infrastructure updates.
- Identify the risks that can delay the release and manage them, such that the scope scheduled, and quality of the release is not affected.
- Track the progress and find issues, if any. Always work to improve the process of release.
- Make sure that the release is planned, according to the requirements and budget.
- Schedule the release readiness reviews before deployment and milestone reviews after each release.
- Create plans for the implementation and deployment as per the release schedule.
- Plan and give weekly updates on the release activities.
- Make sure the allocation of Release Engineers to every release.
- Communicate with release managers from different IT departments.
- Lead the Go-Live activities to deploy the software successfully.
- Team up with relevant development teams responsible for building the automation tools used to develop and deploy the software.
- Schedule the CAB meetings to discuss the release schedules with the team and find roadblocks, if any.
- Maintain documentation related to procedures on build and release, various notifications lists, and dependencies.
- Make improvements in the methodologies used for configuration management and development of software that helps to find ways to use in configuration management.
- Conduct Retrospective meetings for every release.

Senior Software Engineer, Micro Point Computer Limited -MPCL (Client LTFS), November 2020-May 2022

Mumbai

Prepare and manage Release plan/Release calendar for major/ minor releases for a year Forward Plan the release windows and cycles across a portfolio. Responsible for the release during post-release and stabilization phase.

Monitoring and driving overall development process from gathering requirements to deploying in the Production environment. Working closely with in house operations team to automate existing processes in order to increase efficiency.

Preparing/Reviewing the documents (Solution Documents, Business Requirements Document, SOP's & Project Plan) to promote better functionality for clients.

Conduct Release Readiness reviews, Milestone Reviews, and Business

Go/No-Go reviews Produce Deployment,

Run Books and Implementation Plans

Communicate release details and schedules to the Business as required

Senior Software Engineer, Clover Infotech (Client LTFS), April 2020-November 2020 Mumbai

- Working on Git Hub library, Deploy patch on sales force through Eclipse
- Ability to work with Product Owners, Release Managers, to ensure the quality of the software merging to a release
- SCM solutions Perforce/GitHub), CI solutions (Jenkins), Atlassian tools (JIRA),
- Experience working with Git source control code lines, branching, merging, versioning, etc
- Deploys applications and maintain the shared infrastructure, Provide support on the various technologies in use
- Maintains the build environment, the version control system, continuous Integration, defect tracking, collaboration and other supporting tools
- Verifying and certifying Multi product(s) for installation, configuration, dependencies and functionalities including the underlying Database objects (schemas, tables, columns, indexes) and compiled Multi application files (Forms, Reports, BI Publisher reports, EAR files) etc.

Senior Software Engineer, Onward E Services (Client LTFS), October 2018-April 2020 Mumbai

- Deploy the patches through PIM server
- Upload patches WINSCP server
- Deploy patches to putty server
- We check patches on UAT server Knowledge about change and release management and BRD (Business Required Documents),
- Purging table, rebuilding the indexes
- Change management Work with QA, Release Management and L2 Support teams to ensure Quality Rollouts
- Interacted with the business users, collected the requirements, analyse the requirements, design and recommend solutions
- Experience in advance SQL Programming Using Analytical functions, Sub Queries, indexes and so on
- Proficient in creation, modification and effectively use of database objects like

Senior Application Support Engineer, T & M consulting Pvt Limited (Client TCS), May 2015-July 2018

pune

- Assign roll out plan for site engineer to implement L'Oréal application
- Tracking issue of BDE and ASM for L'Oréal application
- Experience on Supply chain management of FMCG
- TCS Help desk support to assist L'Oréal Distributors for both DMS and Hand held, ensuring a high level of performance and making sure that all Distributors calls and complaints are addressed properly
- Maintain the Client Central Console Database which is main database for L'Oréal
- Interacting with end Users and Clients and understanding CR action (Modification requirement in application) Resolve issues like Inconsistency in Database and DB Suspects, Backup and Restore, Point in time recovery
- Identifies & assigns appropriate roles to team members
- Supports & provides to team to achieve personal team &professional goals
- On-call troubleshooting experience
- Handling Product and Pricing management, Purchase order management, Secondary sales stock management, Trade Promotions Management, Claims Management and Distributor Sales Force Automation
- Handling PDA based application for L'Oréal client application
- Experience on writing/modifying scripts using PL/SQL, Microsoft Excel, Manage- engine ticketing tool
- Excellent Problem solving, Analytically and communication skills
- Working on SQL Server2008 migration from SQL Server 2005
- Project implementation and support
- Experience in Installation, Configuration, Maintenance and Administration of SQL Server 2000/2005/2008
- Generating and Maintaining MIS Reports that will adhere to key corporate requirements in a regular, systematic, and logical manner and preparing Power Point Presentations
- Controlling daily ticket resolution/prioritization as client and user volume increases
- Prioritizing issues based on client expectations, volume of current tickets, and visibility of issues across the enterprise

Application Support Engineer, Botree International Software Pvt Ltd, September 2014-March 2015

New Delhi

- Project implementation and support
- Experience in Installation, Configuration, Maintenance and Administration of SQL Server 2000/2005/2008. Very good experience in Installation, configuration, maintenance, monitoring and administration of SQL Server 2005/2008R2.

SENIOR PRESS EXECUTIVE, JUST IN PRINT, September 2011-September 2014 New Delhi

 JIP is the "Youngest Journal" edited by putative Journalists, multi-media initiative for participatory reportage and analyses related to governance of all institutions and processes that are vital to public life in India Currently, Just in Print walked out At present Just IN Print has more than 7 Lakhs Reader's across the globe We aim to become one of the largest print network houses in the coming days

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Application programming
- Database design and implementation
- Oracle /SQL scripting, Unix, , LINUX,
- Release/Change management
- Shell scripting, Linux administration
- Windows Server, DevOps, Devops tools
- Waterfall methodology, DevOps and Agile methodologies
- Data migration, Application Release
 Automation tools such as HCL automation
- Business Analysis, Project Management
 Operations, Testing, and Change
 management in Banking and Supply chain
 Domain.

EDUCATION

MCA & BCA IGNOU

FAMILY:

• father: Golok Narayan Pandey

• Mother: Chameli Devi

DOB

04-10-1984